♪From primal chaos to the starry sky♪
♪In the whole world,
we shall hold the balance♪
♪The cauldron tempers divine blades♪
♪The furnace refines the empty void♪
♪The Way is in mystic fate♪
♪Be brave enough to split
the primal chaos wide open♪
[Pull Strings]
[Adapted from the novel
by Yan Gui Zheng Zhuan]
[Episode 30]
In these five hundred years,
don't you feel we forgot something?
Like,
how did we first meet?
why are we dressed like this?
And
don't you think
Bear Island is missing someone?
If the heart is there,
the sword is there.
Who told these words
to me?
Such a familiar scent.
[Hall of United Spirits]
Mentor.
The celestial music drifts
like a spring breeze.
Yunxiao, your mastery of music
may now surpass mine.
In return,
I shall give you tonight's painting...
Deity,
all is ready as you ordered.
What is happening?
Who opened the Water Dragon Spout?
We do not know.
East Sea warriors!
On guard!
Yes.
I came first.
And me.
Aunt.
Xuanya.
Junior.
Ling'e.
Mentor, are you all right?
Aunt.
You...
Your Majesty,
why so plainly dressed today?
Why are you
here so late?
Again?
I brought them here.
Fairy Yunxiao,
you barged in here.
What is your intent?
Youqin Xuanya,
your inner demon once stopped you
from using your flame art.
Who helped you overcome it?
Qi Yuan,
you once had a deep feud
with Kuai Si of Mistveil Division.
Who aided you in your revenge
and killing Kuai Si?
Yes.
My foundation was ruined.
I could not defeat Kuai Si.
Who helped me?
That remains a mystery
in Ascendance Sect.
Five hundred years ago,
the Way bonds surged
in the Mortal Realm.
Who helped you?
I worked hard at matchmaking.
Answer me.
Who helped you?
I do not know.
Five hundred years ago,
you had no power to transform
into a dragon.
How could you become the Dragon King?
Who helped you train in the Mortal Realm
and return for the succession struggle?
When we met at Bear Stockade,
besides you, Hua Ritian, and me,
there was one more person.
Do you not remember who he was?
I...
Five hundred years ago,
there was once someone.
Do none of you remember him?
Back then,
Yuan Qing of Mistveil Division hurt me
and left me with an inner demon.
With my cultivation then,
I could never escape it.
But I still cannot recall
who they were.
This pendant's design
is truly unique.
Somehow,
it feels deeply familiar to me.
I asked everyone in Ascendance Sect,
but no one knew
who had given it to me.
I keep feeling
I'm not the only
Jade Division disciple.
Mentor, do you know Evasion Art?
My foundation was ruined.
How could I know Evasion Art?
True.
Of all arts under heaven,
I alone master Evasion Art.
If you did not teach me, Mentor,
then who else could it be?
Yes, yes.
And in my mind,
these words often arise:
Live in peace,
think of trouble.
Stay steady, shun karma.
These words are crystal clear in my mind
as if I'd written them a thousand times.
Sometimes,
I even write them down.
But
I asked everyone.
No one knew
where those lines came from.
So, you do remember.
You all remember.
If someone truly helped me grow up,
please tell me who it was.
Yunxiao, I want to know too.
We all do.
Wait.
Don't let this go off track.
I have a question.
If such a person truly exists,
and all of us forgot him,
Fairy Yunxiao,
why do you still remember?
Because I once shared
a spiritual bond with him.
I know everything
he went through.
I have decided
about what you asked me before.
I am willing.
From now on, I will stay
by your side forever.
♪See mortal joys and sorrows♪
[Formation, Evasion Art]
♪Reunions and partings, as fate unfolds♪
♪Alas, love has many twists and turns♪
♪Memories filled with sorrow♪
Little rascal.
After struggling for 3,600 years,
in the end, he gave himself up
to bring us all back.
♪Tearfully,
this life's bond is not over♪
It was his sacrifice
that won peace for the Primordial World.
Senior.
But actually,
these five centuries
were never peaceful.
He created a special space
without Jin Chan for us.
I came to the East Sea this time
to find that star.
I will bring the little rascal back.
Do you think that is possible?
He is with Fate.
Yes.
As long as we have her.
Me?
The Chaos Bell.
The Chaos Bell?
The Chaos Bell has one power.
It can reverse time and space.
Yunxiao, how do you know that?
I did not know at first.
But in his plans over 3,600 years,
he once tried using the Chaos Bell
to reverse time and space.
Even so,
the Great Tribulation remained.
But if we can use it,
we can return to the moment
before he met Fate
and save him.
Save Senior.
I will go with you
to bring him back.
Do not open the Chaos Bell!
You must not open it!
Father.
Do not open the Chaos Bell.
Fairy Yunxiao,
for your own wish,
would you erase these 500 years?
Yes.
You fiend!
Do you know how many beings will perish
if you turn back 500 years?
Do you know
these 500 years were never at peace?
It was he who let us live here
and bore all the pain alone.
But if you turn back 500 years
and save him,
what of the Great Tribulation?
That is why
I waited for 500 years.
500 years ago,
I found him
and asked him to help me.
Yunxiao,
you didn't ask me at all.
When I refused, you beat me.
Each time I refused, you beat me.
I lost count of the beatings.
What did he do?
The same as before.
He posed as a deity
and made the Bear Stockade folks
quarry stone.
I swear.
I was ready to mend my ways
and turn over a new leaf.
She forced me into it.
Do you know
why I have lived on Bear Island
for these five hundred years?
Wasn't it
to keep me company?
The people of Bear Island
are Ancestral Witch heirs.
They were born upon this land
and will be buried beneath it.
The soil of Bear Island
is made of Witch heirs' bodies.
And what of it?
Through the little rascal, I heard
the Sea-Calming Pillar's origin.
It was made by a Quasi-Saint
from Witch remains over 500 years old.
I see.
Its origin was long a mystery.
We judged only by its material
that it was ancient beyond thought,
perhaps older than creation.
Thus, it's an innate magic instrument.
Wait.
A Quasi-Saint?
Five hundred years?
Fairy Yunxiao, you...
I made a new Sea-Calming Pillar.
Once I'm back to 500 years ago,
I will suppress the Demon Emperor.
The Chaos Bell can reverse time
and preserve memory and magical power.
These 500 years of peace
were truly hard-won.
Everyone's holiday is over.
Pack up and get back to work.
Fairy Yunxiao,
how will you take back
the Pillar you refined?
You surely didn't...
Little rascal.
Yunxiao.
It has been 500 years.
At last, I have found you.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Why are you here?
Yunxiao, don't!
You cannot stop me
from making my decisions.
Little rascal,
do you still remember
what you last told me 500 years ago?
You said
you would stay
by my side forever.
Was it true?
I will.
I will stay
by your side forever.
If you ascend, so will I.
If you become a hermit, so will I.
I'll follow you wherever you go,
with no excuses
or deceit.
I would give up all I have pursued
these thirty years
just to bring you back.
Senior,
I brought everyone back.
[500 years ago]
Why?
Why can't I ever defeat you?
I will not accept this.
Yunxiao.
I'm here!
♪But the years are full of chaos♪
♪Caught in karma, stained by dust♪
Time to show Jade Division's power.
Break!
♪Lost in fated secrets♪
Now comes the true finishing move.
♪Let them all come♪
♪There's a perfect plan for everything♪
♪Who's clamoring behind♪
Take Ling'e away first.
Yes.
♪I steadily divine the world's fate♪
♪Who plots and schemes♪
♪And set formations in the world♪
♪I will go in and stir things up♪
It is time
to meet the hero of this era.
♪Some will defy fate♪
Ao Yi.
With your cultivation,
how dare you oppose me?
He is not alone.
I am here too.
Today,
I, Bian Zhuang,
turn over a new leaf.
♪Someone will answer for me♪
♪Only my bonds are priceless♪
♪Taking our steps together♪
It's been a thousand years.
It's time to wake up.
♪Who's clamoring behind♪
♪Acting like fierce demons♪
♪I steadily divine the world's fate♪
♪Who plots and schemes♪
♪And set formations in the world♪
Stop right there.
Your Majesty,
I can't speak at length now.
Don't block my way.
Don't go.
♪Battling fierce demons♪
So, you knew.
She told me to stop you.
She knows
you are set on the Celestial Court,
so you'll heed my words.
She doesn't want you to stop her.
Make way.
Don't you dare!
Even in death, I'll save her.
Wouldn't she do the same?
Changshou, go!
- I'll hold him.
- Thanks, Moon Elder.
Moon Elder!
What are you doing?
Go, now!
Let go of me!
I'll demote you to the Mortal Realm!
Then do it.
I've long been sick
of the Marriage Division post.
Demote me, then.
Changshou, hurry!
Even Fate
will be moved by love.
This body...
How did it come to this?
Demon Emperor,
do you
still like this body?
What exactly did you do?
I have refined this body.
From now on, you are sealed by me,
never to rise again.
You caught my dark soul?
Do not forget:
I came from the first cloud.
You underestimated me.
Release me!
Let go!
Yunxiao!
Little rascal?
Little rascal, why are you here?
You will be sealed too.
Go, now!
I will not leave.
I came to keep my promise.
What promise?
I wish to stay
with you forever.
Do you know
it took me 500 years to save you?
And I spent 3,600 years
to bring you back.
In this lifetime,
I've told so many lies.
But this time, I won't deceive you.
Will you stay by my side?
I will.
♪Memories filled with sorrow♪
♪Slowly, wishes turn to regret♪
♪You've gone afar, like mist fading♪
♪Tearfully,
this life's bond is not over♪
♪Past fragments vanish into night♪
But I cannot do it.
Why?
Little rascal,
heed my order:
Guard all living souls
in this world for me.
The Great Tribulation must never return.
If you cannot do this,
I will never spare you.
♪Slowly, wishes turn to regret♪
Yunxiao!
This is my final wish.
You must grant it.
♪Past fragments vanish into night♪
Move aside!
Jin Chan.
Pay with your life.
Impressive.
Though you do not remember,
I once said
that if we ever met again,
I would kill you myself.
I defied the Celestial Emperor.
Punish me as you wish.
Fairy Yunxiao
asked me to give this to you.
Back then, the Demon Emperor
turned a single hair
into a golden lotus
to hold his soul and bring himself back.
Why can't we do the same
for Fairy Yunxiao?
Fairy Yunxiao is not dead.
Her soul remains within this.
If we rebuild her body,
she can come back.
However,
rebuilding a body
is no ordinary divine art.
Only one with deep cultivation...
I will do it.
You?
This will be very difficult.
We should ask
the Grand Mage of Voidcity.
As I said,
I will do it.
Even if it takes ages,
I will master the arts
and bring her back.
This must not be left to others.
It must be me.
Senior.
Changshou.
Senior Changshou.
♪Making me lean down
and confirm slowly♪
♪Not knowing what love truly is♪
♪Just as it was at first♪
♪Day after day, with whom to share♪
♪Never walked the road
of joy and sorrow♪
♪No better than a mortal♪
♪Not knowing love's depth♪
♪Who truly cares♪
Long time no see.
♪At storm's end,
stars gleam, and clouds drift♪
♪Together we smile,
watching moonrise and sunset♪
[Easter egg]
Senior,
you
play
it
safe.
♪I don't ask, too lazy to fight♪
♪I dare to live my own way♪
♪In the Primordial World♪
♪Who sings and drinks free♪
♪The stars smile at fireflies♪
♪Roaming the city with reckless courage♪
Amazing.
Junior.
Give me one more chance.
Senior.
♪Who can ever♪
♪Predict the clock of time♪
Who's the mentor here, you or me?
♪The hearth smoke rises high♪
Little rascal.
I saw your every move coming.
♪A varied life♪
Thanks to your help,
I can manage so well.
♪I drink the breeze that comes my way♪
♪The steadiest surge of all♪
♪I grasp the vast firmament♪
♪Karma never falls empty♪
♪Let the thoughts weigh♪
♪Will fulfill our original vow♪
♪Unruly♪
♪A carefree smile♪
I am here.
Leave it all to me.
Rest easy.
So carefree and noble.
Truly a lofty vision,
a broad mind.
Changgeng,
you're human, right?
Do not come at me!
♪I scorn to ride the eastern wind♪
♪Not hiding from fate's pursuit♪
♪In this Primordial World♪
♪Who's out there sword riding♪
I am an Aureate Immortal.
How could you rival me?
Impossible.
For loyalty.
Charge!
♪No one can predict the clock of time♪
♪Then please, just relax♪
♪How many night watches have passed by♪
[The Sea Deity can grant great power!]
Do you want to join us?
♪Let the answer be empty♪
Blood for blood!
Go ahead.
Cut.
♪I grasp the vast firmament♪
[Lost?]
♪Let the thoughts weigh♪
♪Will fulfill our original vow♪
♪Unruly♪
♪A carefree smile♪
Come, come!
Pull Strings!
[South Heavenly Gate]
Li Changshou of Ascendance Sect
has served the Celestial Court
many times
with sincere dedication
and moved the heavens above.
In the name of the Celestial Emperor,
I hereby issue this imperial decree:
Li Changshou is appointed Water Deity
of the Three Realms.
Li Changshou,
receive the decree.
Li Changshou used to be
so eager to come here before.
Now that I'm bestowing a title on him,
how dare he stand me up?
What does "stand up" mean?
Leave.
I've been looking for you everywhere.
Yi said you were here.
I did not believe it.
Yet here you are.
In the past,
we doubted and tested each other.
We even fought without end.
Who would have thought
we would become such close friends?
From now on,
I shall call you little brother.
What do you think?
So, I have reached the point
of being brothers with the Dragon King.
Of course.
Because you play it safe.
Right.
Why didn't you take office
at Celestial Court?
The Great Tribulation is gone.
Why rush to the Celestial Court?
Then why
don't you stay at Ascendance Sect?
I just think
it's nice to keep her company.
As for that Great Tribulation,
it was all my own pride.
I'm truly grateful to you
and Fairy Yunxiao.
You showed me
that I was terribly foolish.
Thank you for guiding my son, Ao Yi.
You brought the East Sea Dragon Clan
to the Celestial Court,
so we no longer live
in fear.
You're now a hands-off ruler.
How does that feel?
It feels great.
It's just wonderful.
Had I known that,
why fuss over petty schemes now?
Little brother,
I've noticed something.
You're much like Fairy Yunxiao.
In what way?
You both love standing here,
gazing at the Sea-Calming Pillar.
What a coincidence.
And stranger still,
deep in your hearts,
you both have other aims.
Yet neither of you will say it.
But rest easy.
If you won't speak, I won't ask.
I am but a muddled old dragon now.
I'm of no use anymore.
Oh, right.
Yi said just now
that more seek the Sea Deity Grandlord.
He can't handle it alone.
Do help him when you can.
Go have a look.
Very well, little brother.
I'll take my leave.
Though you do not remember,
I once said
that if we ever met again,
I would kill you myself.
Why is Yunxiao saving the world?
Why not you?
What are you laughing at?
I was wrong.
We were all wrong.
Wrong about what?
So,
there are two Chosen Ones,
and there are two Great Tribulations.
The heroine of this tribulation
is Yunxiao.
And you
are the hero of the next tribulation.
Li Changshou,
in our next life,
we shall meet again.
Yunxiao.
I will guard
your wish to the end.
[To be continued]
♪See mortal joys and sorrows♪
♪Reunions and partings, as fate unfolds♪
♪Alas, love has many twists and turns♪
♪Memories filled with sorrow♪
♪Slowly, wishes turn to regret♪
♪You've gone afar, like mist fading♪
♪Tearfully,
this life's bond is not over♪
♪Past fragments vanish into night♪
♪Down a few more cups of wine♪
♪Through land and sea,
I ask you to come♪
♪For honor's sake, upright and grand♪
♪Alas, our story is short♪
♪Slowly, wishes turn to regret♪
♪You've gone afar, like mist fading♪
♪Tears fall, this fate's not done♪
♪Past fragments vanish into night♪